<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trevor Bhattacharya</title>
    <link>https://trevorb.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trevor Bhattacharya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trevorb.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://trevorb.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trevorb.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Trevor. 👋
I’m an engineer at heart–always looking to better understand the world around me. I am always learning.
I’ve lived in Colorado, Kansas City (both the Kansas and Missouri sides), and eastern Washington. I currently reside in Portland, OR.
I love to travel, explore, and read. You can usually find my wife and me hiking somewhere new, biking, or sipping coffee.
I have over 5 years of experience leading technical and industrial, data based projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and Railroad Projects</title>
      <link>https://trevorb.io/projects/railroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trevorb.io/projects/railroad/</guid>
      <description>Terminal Process Control I traveled across BNSF Railway&#39;s system developing and testing Terminal Process Control (TPC) in BNSF&#39;s major rail hubs. My experience with this project inspired me to pursue a full-time career in data science!
TPC is a modern control system for automatically sorting train cars at classification (hump) yards. 160-ton train cars are rolled down a hill while TPC controls their speed and routes them to a destination. The largest yards process over 2000 cars per day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Scooter Utilization in Python</title>
      <link>https://trevorb.io/projects/scooters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trevorb.io/projects/scooters/</guid>
      <description>Predicting Scooter utilization Using Machine learning to improve strategic placement of scooters in Austin, TX. Check out the github page.
Project description: Now ubiquitous, the electric scooter cruises through bike lanes and sidewalks of every major US city. In order to stay competitive, operating companies need to ensure their scooters or e-bikes are highly utilized. They must ensure that their fleets are in place to meet demand. Using data provided by the city of Austin, TX, I implemented various machine learning strategies to predict optimal fleet distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognizing Bengali Graphemes using CNNs</title>
      <link>https://trevorb.io/projects/bengali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trevorb.io/projects/bengali/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Unlike English, Bengali letters are not separated symbols, but rather a combination of different types of symbols. Bengali ‘letters’ are a combination of at least one of the following: consonant, vowel diacritic, and a consonant diacritic. The combination of these can result in approximately 13,000 possible graphemes.
The aim of this project is to classify the dataset of handwritten graphemes. This allows computer vision to read Bengali words, with an alphabet that (to me, a native English-speaker) is much more complicated than the latin alphabet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>